That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
Episode 5: Hero King, Gazel Dwargo
（カイジン）ハッハッハッハ！
Man, that sure threw me for a loop!
しかし 恐れ入ったよ
I busted my ass to make that sword,
and you made all those copies in seconds!
俺の渾身(こんしん)の ひと振りが
まさか あっという間に
量産されちまうとはね
Only because the original
you made was so incredible.
（リムル）
カイジンの作ったオリジナルが
すばらしかったからな
All I did was analyze it
俺は ただ それを解析して
魔鉱塊(まこうかい)を使ってコピーしただけだ
and use that magisteel cluster to copy it.
Was I out of line?
（リムル）余計なマネだったかな？
If I'm being honest, it is a little vexing...
正直 思うところはあるが…
But next time, I'll make one so amazing
that even you won't be able to copy it!
次は旦那にも
絶対 マネできないような
すっごいやつを
作ってみせるってもんだ
I relish the challenge!
腕が鳴るぜ！
That's the spirit!
（リムル）そうこなくっちゃ！
（カイジン）ぷは〜っ！
（リムル）ママさん おかわり！
Refill, please!
Can you even taste this?
（店のママ）
スライムさん 味 分かるの？
I can't, but any drink is delicious
if a pretty lady pours it for me!
（リムル）分からないけど
きれいな人に お酌してもらえたら
何でもおいしく感じるんだ
Oh, very smooth!
あら お上手ね
Here you go.
さあ どうぞ
It's nice being the one entertained for once.
（リムル）
接待される側ってのはいいなあ
As a human, I was always the
one doing the entertaining.
人間だったときは する側で
いろいろ気ぃ使ったもんな
There was a lot I had to be attentive to.
Ah, this is paradise!
ああ… 天国だ
Meanwhile, Gobta had been
completely forgotten.
（リムル）
ちなみにゴブタは
すっかり忘れ去られていた
（エルフＡ）
ねえねえ スライムさん
Hey, Mr. Slime!
Would you like to try this?
これ やってみない？
I'm very good at it.
（エルフＡ）私 得意なんだよ
Everyone says I'm pretty amazing, in fact.
結構すごいって評判なんだから
（リムル）
おお〜！
こ… これは あの伝説の！
C-Could this be the legend I've heard about?!
（エルフＡ）あっ あ〜ん
Is she gonna do that...
（リムル）
あんなことや…
（エルフＡ）あ〜ん いや〜ん
No!
（リムル）
ああ〜 そんなことまで！
and even that?!
Uh, th-that's...
あっ！　そっ そこは…
M-Ma'am, we mustn't...
お… 奥さん
そんな… いっ いけません！
Mr. Slime?
（エルフＡ）スライムさん？
（リムル）奥さん…
Ma'am... Ma'am...
（リムル）奥さん！
（エルフＡ）スライムさん！
Mr. Slime!
（エルフＡ）準備はいい？
（リムル）えっ？
Are you ready?
Oh. She meant fortunetelling.
（リムル）
あっ なんだ… 占いか
So what kind of reading can you do?
（リムル）
それで 何を占ってくれるんだ？
ん〜 そうねえ　何がいい？
Well...
What would you like?
How about the person he's
destined to be with?
（エルフＢ）
スライムさんの運命の人とか！
Huh?
Oh, good idea!
（エルフＡ）あっ それ いいかも
Okay, here I go.
（エルフＡ）
じゃあ 占っちゃうよ〜
え〜い！
What's this? I can't see anything.
あれ？　何も映らな〜い
（リムル）おい！
Hey!
（一同の笑い声）
（エルフＡ）冗談 冗談
I'm just kidding.
You're so silly, Mr. Slime!
（エルフＢ）
もう スライムさんたら！
（リムル）えっ 俺？
Huh? Me?
Okay, for real this time.
じゃあ 今度は本気でいくわよ
The person I'm destined to be with...
運命の人か…
Could someone like that
really be in this world?
この世界に
そんな人がいるのかなあ
人っていうか
運命のスライムだったり…
Maybe it's actually a slime
I'm destined to be with.
Oh, I see something!
（エルフＡ）
あっ なんか見えてきた
She sort of looked Japanese...
（リムル）
なんか日本人っぽいな
That was one pretty girl.
（カイジン）きれいな人だったなあ
You're turning red.
赤くなってるぞ
Huh?!
I don't change colors!
って 色 変わんないって
あ〜 スライムさん
運命の人 気になるんだ
Oh, you're curious about this girl
you're destined to be with, huh?
No fair, cheating on us!
ずる〜い 浮気者
Sure, I'm curious, but...
（リムル）気になるっていうか…
Destined, huh?
（リムル）
運命の人か…
同じ日本人なら会ってみたいな
If she's also Japanese,
I guess I'd like to meet her.
Should you really be wasting
time in a place like this,
（ベスター）
いいんですか？
こんな所で のんびりしてて
Kaijin?
（ベスター）カイジン殿
It's Minister Vesta.
大臣のベスターだ
So that's him?
（リムル）あれが うわさの…
He looks pretty stubborn and high-strung.
（リムル）
神経質で ねちっこそう
Is this a good time to be playing around?
遊んでいる場合なのですかな？
I believe the deadline for
those longswords is...
確か
ロングソードの納品の期限は…
I just sent them in.
さっき納めてきた
If you don't get them finished in time...
期限に間に合わなければ…
What? You sent them in?!
えっ 納めてきた？
Yep. All twenty of them.
（カイジン）ああ きっちり20本
B-But that's...
（ベスター）そっ そんな…
Want to see the invoice?
（カイジン）納品書を確認するか？
Is that so?
そうですか　受けた仕事を…
Well, well, finishing your work in
the time allotted is to be expected.
Did this Minister Vesta guy knowingly
give him an impossible order?
（リムル）
あのベスターとかっていう大臣
無理だと分かってて発注したのか
Yes, it's only to be expected.
Doesn't look like they're on good terms...
仲悪そうだもんな
I'm more concerned with that!
（ベスター）
それよりも それですよ それ！
Huh? Me?
（リムル）えっ 俺？
いけませんな
You shouldn't bring such a lowly monster
into a high-brow establishment like this.
この上品な店に
下等な魔物などを連れ込んでは
It's making me feel ill.
気分が悪くなる
Hey! Do you allow monsters
to be brought in here?
おい この店は
魔物の連れ込みを許すのか？
It may be a monster, but it
seems like a harmless slime.
魔物といいましても
無害そうなスライムですし
What?
はあ？　魔物だろうが
違うのか？
It is a monster, am I wrong?
Are you trying to say slimes aren't monsters?
スライムは魔物じゃないとでも
ぬかすか！
No, not in the least.
（店のママ）
いえ そのようなわけでは決して…
まあまあ 大臣様
一杯いかがですか？
Come, now, Minister. How about a drink?
さあ どうぞ
Please, help yourself.
Hmph. This is what should
be done to monsters.
（ベスター）フンッ
魔物には こうするのが お似合いよ
（エルフＢ）きゃあ！
Mr. Slime!
スライムさん？
Don't worry. I'm okay.
（リムル）
大丈夫だよ おねえさん
ドレス ぬれなかった？
Did your dress get wet?
I-I'm fine...
（エルフＢ）あ… はい
That made me mad,
（リムル）
カチンとはきたが
相手は大臣だからな
but the guy's a minister.
I can't let my short temper screw
things up for Kaijin and this bar.
俺の短気でカイジンや この店に
迷惑はかけられない
Fruit wine. Alcohol content: 7%.
Fruit Wine
（大賢者(だいけんじゃ)）
果実酒
Fruit
Wine
(Carbonated)
Only those 20 or older should drink alcohol.
Enjoy in moderation, and be sure to recycle the container afterward.
Alcohol Content
アルコール濃度
７パーセント
Uh, Great Sage, I don't
need that info right now.
（リムル）
いや 大賢者
そんな情報はいいから
（カイジン）ふん！
Vesta!
ベスター！　俺の客に
ナメたマネしてくれやがって
I hope you're prepared to pay
for treating my guest like that.
覚悟はできてるんだろうな？
Y-You...
きっ 貴様！
私に対して そのような口を…
How dare you speak to me like that?!
Shut up!
黙れ！
Hey, Kaijin!
（ドルド）カイジンさん
Go easy on him!
（ガルム）ほどほどにね
Not the face! Go for the body!
（リムル）
顔はヤバいよ ボディーだよ
（カイジン）ふん！
（ベスター）うっ！
Was that a good idea? Isn't he a minister?
（リムル）
いいの？　そいつ 大臣なんだろ？
Won't this mean trouble for you?
面倒なことにならない？
Hey, Rimuru...
（カイジン）
リムルの旦那
腕のいい職人を探してたよな？
You were looking for skilled artisans, right?
Would you settle for me?
俺じゃダメかい？
What?! You mean it?
（リムル）えっ！　いいの？
I don't need to settle if I have you!
ダメどころか大歓迎だよ！
I'd be thrilled to have your help, Kaijin!
こちらこそ よろしく頼む
カイジン！
But things rarely work out
so smoothly in this world.
（リムル）
しかし そう簡単にはいかないのが
世の中である
（カイドウ）
なあ 兄貴… 何やってんだよ
C'mon, Bro, what were you thinking?
Hmph. That moron there was
rude to my buddy Rimuru.
フン！
そこのバカが リムルの旦那に
失礼なことしやがるから
I just gave him a little scolding.
ちょいと お灸(きゅう)を据えてやったのよ
"A little"?
ちょいとって…
大臣相手に それはマズいだろう
You know you can't do that to a minister.
フンッ
Hmph.
Don't hold this against me.
It's just the law.
悪く思うなよ　決まりだからな
兄貴たちの身柄は
裁判まで 一旦 拘束させてもらう
I'll have to keep you all
restrained until your trial.
Move.
おい
It's just our job, you know.
（兵士）俺たちも仕事なんで
Trial?
（リムル）裁判？
You've been asleep all this time?!
（リムル）
ロングスリーパーか！
ハア…
If only I hadn't lost my temper...
俺が
短気を起こしちまったばっかりに…
みんなも巻き込んじまった
I dragged you all into this.
I'm sorry.
すまん！
大丈夫！　問題ないさ
Hey, it's okay! No problem!
親父(おやじ)さんが気にすることないですよ
Nothing you need to worry about!
Speak, man!
（リムル）
しゃべれよ！
Are we going to be put on trial?
（リムル）
俺たちは裁判を受けるのか？
Yeah, I guess so.
（カイジン）まあ そうなるな
We won't be executed or anything, though.
まっ でも 死刑にはならんさ
We'll probably just have to pay a fine.
罰金ぐらいで済むだろう
I hope so...
（リムル）なら いいが…
But that minister really
seemed to have it in for you.
あの大臣 えらくカイジンを
目の敵(かたき)にしてたようだが…
俺は この国の王ガゼル･ドワルゴに
仕えていたんだ
I used to serve this nation's
king, Gazel Dwargo.
７つある王宮騎士団の
そのひとつの団長だった
I was the captain of one of the
seven orders of royal knights.
At the time, he was my adjutant.
ヤツは そのときの部下…
副官だった
He came from the marquis's family,
侯爵(こうしゃく)の出(で)でな
and I was from a family of peasants.
俺は庶民の出だったし
面白くなかったんだろう
It must have infuriated him.
Even back then, we clashed all the time.
当時から よく衝突していた
And then...
そんなとき…
One of the projects he'd been under pressure
to complete, the Magisoldier Project...
（カイジン）
功を焦ったベスターの計画のひとつ
魔装兵(まそうへい)計画が…
went up in smoke.
（カイジン）
ポシャっちまった
ベスターは
自分の失敗を
Vesta foisted all the responsibility
for his failure onto me.
全て俺に押しつけた
He got our forces on his side and
even came up with false testimony.
軍の幹部を抱き込み
偽(にせ)の証言まで用意してな
So I assumed responsibility
and quit the force.
で 俺は責任を取って
軍を辞めたってわけだ
あいつは いまだに
何かというと俺を目の敵にして
He still holds a grudge against me and
makes unreasonable demands
of me at every opportunity.
無理難題をふっかけてくる
That's what this was all about, too.
まあ 今回の件もそうだが
He's pretty pathetic.
（リムル）しょうもないヤツだな
You got that right.
そうだな
But it's not as if he's a bad guy, really.
ただ ヤツも
別に悪人ってわけじゃないんだ
He and I weren't a good match,
俺とは馬が合わなかったが
もともと研究熱心で努力家だ
but he was always a hard worker
and passionate about his research.
The pressure he felt to complete that project
came from his need to please the king.
功を焦ったのも 王の期待に
応えようとした結果だしな
If I leave this country,
it might make him a better man.
俺が この国から出ていけば
あいつも少しはマシになるかもな
You really think so?
（リムル）
そんなものかねえ
Well, Rimuru...
（カイジン）リムルの旦那
I'm all yours.
世話になるぜ
Thanks.
About that...
（ガルム）それなんですけど…
俺たちも
カイジンさんについていきます
We're gonna follow Kaijin, too.
Yeah.
（ドルド）そうっす
We'll go anywhere if it means
we can work with Kaijin.
カイジンさんと一緒に働けるなら
どこでも行きます
（ミルド）うんうん
（リムル）やっぱりか
Yeah, I figured.
You guys...
お前たち…
Rimuru, would we be in your
way if we tagged along?
リムルの旦那
俺たちがついていったら迷惑かい？
Heh. I'll be glad to take all of you in!
（リムル）
フンッ
みんなまとめて面倒見てやるさ！
But be ready. I'm gonna
work you to the bone!
こき使うから覚悟しとけよ！
Right!
（２人）おう！
（ミルド）うんうん
He's even silent when he's sleeping.
（リムル）
こいつ
眠ってるときも静かなんだな
Great Rimuru? Did something happen?
（ゴブタ）
リムル様…
何かあったんすか？
He's so carefree...
（リムル）
こいつは本当に
のんきだな
We've got some things to do.
Mind if we leave you here?
（リムル）
俺たちは
ちょっと野暮(やぼ)用があるから
このまま置いていっていいか？
Huh?
If you want to get out,
call your Tempest Wolf partner.
（リムル）抜け出したかったら
相棒のテンペストウルフでも
召喚したまえ
Wait... What?! That's just mean!
（ゴブタ）
ちょっ えっ！
ひどくないっすか？
What am I doing up here,
anyway?! Get me down!
Don't worry. I won't forget to
come back for you when we're done.
（リムル）
安心しろ！　用事が終わったら
忘れずに戻ってくるから
Please let me down!
（ゴブタ）下ろしてください！
（リムル）ぺっ！
（リムル）フウ…
（リムル）
まっ 関係ないのに
裁判に巻き込んでも
I'd feel bad getting him dragged in
to this trial when he wasn't involved.
かわいそうだしな
His Majesty Gazel Dwargo will now enter!
（裁判官補）
ガゼル･ドワルゴ王の ご出馬である
ふむ
The judge presiding over Rimuru's
party is the Hero King of the Dwarves,
（リムル）
リムルたちを裁くのは
ドワーフの英雄王
ガゼル･ドワルゴである
Gazel Dwargo.
Hero King     Gazel Dwargo
Yikes, this guy's bad news! He's a beast!
（リムル）
ヤッベえ この男…
化け物だ
He's obviously strong!
間違いなく強い
（傍仕(そばづか)え）これより 裁判を始める
The trial will now begin.
All rise.
一同起立！
I'm rising.
（リムル）
立ってま〜す
In the Armed Nation of Dwargon,
（リムル）
武装国家ドワルゴン
no one can speak during a trial
without the king's permission.
この国の裁判では
王の許しなく発言はできない
For that reason, a proxy
speaks for the defense...
そのため
弁護には代理人が当たるのだが…
As we have seen, when Minister Vesta was
enjoying a drink in said establishment,
（代理人）と… このように
店で お酒をたしなんでおられた
ベスター殿に対し
カイジンらは複数で店に押し入り
暴行を加えたのです
Kaijin and his gang stormed
the place and assaulted him.
これは断じて
許されるべき行為ではありません
Such behavior must not be tolerated.
He's been bought.
買収されたな
（リムル）
なんだって？
What? Isn't he supposed to be defending us?
弁護してくれるんじゃ
なかったのか？
Also...
ってか あいつ あんなに
ケガしてなかったろうが
I don't remember him being that injured...
それは事実であるか？
Is this true?
Yes. There is no mistake.
はっ！　間違いございませぬ
King Gazel, have you heard all this?
（ベスター）
ガゼル王よ！　お聞き届け
いただけましたでしょうか？
Please pass strict judgment
upon these people!
この者たちへの厳罰を
申し渡しください
Kaijin said Vesta wasn't a bad guy,
（リムル）
カイジンはベスターのこと
悪人じゃないって言ってたけど
but he totally is.
絶対 悪人だろ あいつ
王よ！
Your Majesty!
I will now state the verdict.
（傍仕え）
これより 判決を申し渡す
It doesn't look like we'll get
out of this with just a fine.
（リムル）
これは罰金で済むとは思えないな
I've got a really bad feeling...
やな予感しかしない
The principal offender, Kaijin,
主犯 カイジン
この者は
鉱山での強制労働20年に処す
is sentenced to twenty years
of forced labor in the mines.
Huh?!
そのほか共犯者どもは
鉱山での強制労働10年に処す
And his accomplices are sentenced to
ten years of forced labor in the mines.
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
The court is now adjourned.
（傍仕え）
これにて この裁判を閉廷！
H...
（リムル）
ちょ… ちょ 待てよ！
Hey! Wait just a minute!
（ガゼル）待て！
Wait.
（ガゼル）
久しいな カイジン　息災か？
It's been some time, Kaijin.
Have you been well?
Yes.
Kaijin, you may answer His Majesty.
（傍仕え）
カイジン　答えてよろしい
Yes, Your Majesty.
（カイジン）
はっ！　王におかれましても
ご健勝そうで何よりでございます
I am relieved to find you
in good health, as well.
カイジンよ
Kaijin.
余のもとに戻ってくる気はあるか？
Have you any interest in
returning to my ranks?
恐れながら 王よ
私は 既に主(あるじ)を得ました
Forgive me, Your Majesty,
but I have already found my master.
My sworn oath is my greatest treasure.
この契りは私の宝であります
この宝 たとえ王の命令であれど
手放す気はありませぬ！
I will never part with this treasure,
even if Your Majesty orders it.
（兵士）無礼な！
Insolence!
Wha... You're kidding!
（リムル）
うわっ え… ウソ！
であるか…
I see.
I will now pass judgment.
判決を言い渡す
Kaijin and his companions shall be exiled.
カイジンおよび
その仲間は
国外追放とする
以上である！
That concludes my verdict.
Disappear from my sight at once!
余の前より消えるがよい！
（リムル）
フウ… 国外追放だけで済んだか
We got off with just exile...
Still...
でも… ちょっと寂しそうだな
He seems a little sad.
This court is now adjourned.
（傍仕え）これにて 閉廷！
さて ベスター
何か言いたいことはあるか？
Now then, Vesta, is there
anything you wish to say?
Y-Your Majesty... I...
お… 王よ 私は…
W-Well...
そっ その…
It is unfortunate.
残念だ
I have lost a loyal retainer.
余は忠実な臣を
１人失うこととなった
なっ 何をおっしゃいます！
カイジンなど…
H-How can you say such a thing? Kaijin...
That man did not swear loyalty to you!
あのような者
王に忠誠を誓うどころか
He chose some slime of
unknown background to—
どこの馬の骨とも分からぬ
スライムと…
ベスターよ
お前は勘違いをしておる
Vesta.
You are mistaken.
余が失う忠実な臣
The loyal retainer I have lost...
is, in fact...
それは…
I had great hopes for you.
（ガゼル）
余は お前に期待していたのだ
ずっと待っていた
I waited years, even through the
failure of the Magisoldier Project,
魔装兵事件の際も…
真実を話してくれるのを
for you to tell me the truth.
Y-Your Majesty, please...
（ベスター）
おっ 恐れ… 恐れながら…
And now, as well...
そして 今回も
Look there.
それを見よ
Do you know what that is?
（ガゼル）何か分かるか？
It is a full potion, a draught of complete
recovery, made from hipokute herbs.
ヒポクテ草から作られた完全回復薬
“フルポーション”だ
But...
（ベスター）そんな…
ドワーフの技術の粋(すい)を集めても
98パーセントの抽出が限界のはず
Even with the most advanced
dwarven techniques,
a potion can only achieve
98% recovery at most...
How is this possible?
一体 どうやって…
It was that slime who gave it to us.
それをもたらしたのは
あのスライムだ
Your actions have severed our
relationship with that slime.
お前の行いが
あの魔物とのつながりを絶った
何か言いたいことはあるか！
Now, is there anything you wish to say?
I have nothing to say, Your Majesty.
何も… ございません 王よ
I wanted only to be useful to you.
私は 王の役に立ちたいと…
Ever since I first saw you as a young boy,
幼い日に初めて王を見た日から
that is all I have ever wanted.
ただ それだけで…
私は道を誤ったのか
Did I choose the wrong path?
カイジンに嫉妬したときから
Was it when I began to envy Kaijin?
Or was it even earlier?
あるいは もっと前か…
For betraying Your Majesty's expectations...
王の期待を裏切ってしまい
申し訳ありません
I ask your forgiveness.
Vesta, never show yourself before me again.
（ガゼル）ベスター
二度と
余の前に姿を見せるな
I have one last thing to say to you.
そして 最後に ひと言
お前に言葉を贈ろう
Thank you for your service.
大儀であった！
兄貴 元気でな
Take care of yourself, Bro.
Sorry for all the trouble.
You take care, too.
迷惑をかけたな
お前も元気で
Rimuru, take care of my brother.
リムルの旦那 兄貴を頼む
No need to worry.
I'll only work him to death.
（リムル）
心配いらない　こき使うだけだ
これより判決に従い カイジンと
その一味を国外追放とする
In accordance with the king's sentence,
Kaijin and his companions are now exiled.
Leave at once!
早々に立ち去れ！
Well, shall we get moving?
（リムル）さて 行くか
My friends are waiting in the forest.
森で俺の仲間たちが待ってる
Right.
Despite all that happened,
（リムル）
いろいろあったものの
Rimuru achieved his initial goal
of bringing back some artisans.
職人を連れて帰るという
当初の目的は果たされたのだった
And they happened to be some of
the most skilled artisans around.
それも これ以上ないと言って
いいほどの腕前の職人たちを
代理人は捕らえたな？
厳罰に処せ
You've apprehended the proxy?
Punish him severely.
Of course.
あのスライムの動向を
監視せよ
And observe that slime's movements.
あんな魔物が
解き放たれているとは…
It is unthinkable that such
a monster has been released.
Do not be noticed, no matter what it takes.
絶対に気取(けど)られるなよ
絶対にだ！
Of course.
That slime is a true beast...
（ガゼル）あれは化け物だ
Just like the Storm Dragon, Veldora!
まるで暴風竜ヴェルドラのごとき！
Next time, "Shizu."
（大賢者）
次回「シズ」
Shizu